Chris Benard

Plano, TX, United States 9728367466 chris@chrisbenard.net http://chrisbenard.net

I am an Enterprise Windows Forms/ASP.NET/C# developer focusing on building dynamic web applications that serve the needs of customers. I'm additionally focused on providing backends for mission critical systems like credit card processing, EDI medical claims adjudication, and point of sale signature pad interaction. I am particularly interested in web standards and usability. I have strong experience with Microsoft SQL Server, Windows Forms, Services, Web Services, ASP.NET, and C#. I am additionally experienced in the maintenance of Microsoft Windows servers and computer networking. **Specialties**

C#, ASP.Net, Microsoft SQL Server, TCP and UDP sockets, EDI (NCPDP), Modems, XHTML, XML, HTML, CSS, standards driven programming, usability, code reusability

Technical Skills

Like:

c#, asp.net, asp.net-mvc, wpf, windows, xml, html, xhtml, silverlight, windows-phone, windows-phone-7

Experience

Senior Software Developer – New Tech Computer Systems (Morris & Dickson) asp.net, asp.net-ajax, c#, html, xhtml, javascript, windows-services, edi, credit-card, sql-server

June 2006 - Current

- Designed and created EDI parsers and .Net NCPDP EDI claim switch, along with .Net 1.1 and 2.0/3.5 clients for the server, continuously processing hundreds of thousands of medical pharmacy claims 24/7/365.
- Designed and created new plugin-based credit card server which dynamically loads plug-ins to accommodate
 any new processor at run-time, processing tens of thousands of credit and debit card transactions 24/7/365.
- Implemented automatic-discovery connection string server to allow new clients on the network to automatically discover, via UDP, the correct server and database settings.
- Designed and created interface-based signature pad interface for the Point of Sale system, allowing PoS
 developers to abstract away the communication and polling of serial signature pad devices.
- Designed and implemented remote support program based on UltraVNC single click for the support department and integrated it into the public-facing web site.
- Designed and created, with a coworker, the public facing website for our parent company.
- Wrote brief technical documentation for support department's use in troubleshooting applications

Associate Network Administrator / Software Developer – Highland Clinic php, c#, html, xhtml, javascript, linux, shell-script, mysql

May 2003 - June 2006

- Created content management system still used for http://www.highlandclinic.com, allowing non-technical users
 to edit the website, post billing FAQs, update open jobs, and other tasks.
- · Created integrated document management system for the company intranet.
- Created web reporting management system for the company intranet.
- Automated many manual tasks, freeing up labor for other tasks.
- Created integrated authentication system for the company intranet.
- Designed and implemented Microsoft Active Directory environment, migrating from a hybrid peer-to-peer / NT4 domain network
- Assisted in the design and implementation of WANs and LANs.
- Coordinated the side-wide installation of a secure campus wireless network with an outside contractor.
- Managed orders and purchasing for the IT department, including enterprise hardware and software.

Education

M.S. Business Administration - Louisiana Tech University

2008 - 2010

- GPA: 3.833
- Concentration: Information Assurance

B.S. Computer Information Systems - Louisiana State University in Shreveport

2001 - 2007

- Chancellor's List
- Dean's List
- · 2007 Outstanding Student Award
- Multiple Academic Scholarships
- GPA: 3.48

Projects & Interests

Stack Overflow-http://stackoverflow.com/users/448

August 2008 - Current

Written 32 answers. Active in c#.

GitHub - SimpleOAuth.Net – https://github.com/cbenard/SimpleOAuth.Net c#, silverlight, windows-phone, windowsphone, oauth

March 2012 - April 2012

OAuth for the .Net framework - made super easy.

I created a fork of a project called SimpleOAuth.Net, which is a great tiny library for doing OAuth in C# with minimal overhead. My fork adds support for Windows Phone 7 Mango by making everything async aware.

I created a tester Windows Phone app as well that tests using the term.ie tester OAuth service as well as the Twitter API.

GitHub - kohanafacebook – https://github.com/cbenard/kohanafacebook php, facebook, kohana, mvc

January 2011

Example Kohana application with Facebook integration. Please follow the instructions at: https://github.com/cbenard/kohanafacebook/blob/master/README.md

This is an application I created for my talk at the Dallas PHP User Group. I demonstrated the usage of Kohana V3 MVC framework in PHP while integrating Facebook as the login mechanism for a blog.

The blog was coded live for the demonstration to show how easy it is to leverage Kohana V3 MVC as well as Facebook for Single Sign-On for a website.